# Nilesh Trivedi

CONTACT

Udaipur, Rajasthan, India

hi@nileshtrivedi.com http://nileshtrivedi.com +91.773.7799.743

### **SUMMARY**

I have worked in technology companies and startups across engineering, product management and sales roles for over 8 years. I co-founded a B2B product company with a Social CRM app. With an IIT and IIM background, I am an expert at web and mobile development, product management and analytics. I am very hands-on and still love to code in my spare time. Some of my technical work can be seen here: http://www.nileshtrivedi.com/work.html

I am now looking for product management or engineering roles at early stage startups. I am willing to relocate.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Freelancing

July 2013 — October 2014

Independent Engineer

• Engineering work for startups ranging from web and mobile apps to robotics to hardware, electronics, computer vision and machine learning

### GupShup, Bombay

June 2009 — July 2013

Lead Software Engineer

- Delivered multiple web applications for Enterprise SMSGupShup serving thousands of users and billions of messages per month.
- Development for GupShup's Android app
- Growth marketing with analytics and optimization of ad campaigns

### Lattice Purple Technologies, Noida

March 2008 — June 2009

Co-Founder

- Developed a social CRM app YouSuggest
- Successfully sold it to Indian media enterprises

### VoiceTech Solutions, Bangalore

May 2007 — June 2007

Business Analyst (Intern)

- Developed business plan for expansion into south-east Asia
- Developed the channel partner program

## HeadStrong, Bangalore

October 2005 — May 2006

Senior Associate

- Delivered multiple releases for Nuance Voice Platform
- Developed a number of VoiceXML applications

### Tata Consultancy Services, Bangalore

July 2004 — October 2005

Nilesh Trivedi 1

#### Assistant Software Engineer

■ Development for American Express Global Website

### **EDUCATION**

MBA (Marketing)

July 2006 — March 2008

**IIM Lucknow** 

GPA: 6.00

B.Tech. (AeroSpace Engineering)

July 1999 — May 2003

IIT Kharagpur

GPA: 7.3

### **INTERESTS**

Programming for fun, making music, reading and travelling. Over the years, I have presented at various conferences such as BarCamp, RubyConf, JSFoo, Makerfest etc. I blog at <a href="http://nileshtrivedi.com">http://nileshtrivedi.com</a> and my twitter and github accounts are @nileshtrivedi.

### REFERENCES

Viswanath Ramachandran, Founder, Hippily Email: viswanath.ramachandran@gmail.com

Tathagata Mitra, Product Manager, ZopNow Email: tathagata@gmail.com

Nilesh Trivedi 2